Guide to the Anne Ramsay Somers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1961-1977; Series II; 6 linear feet (12 boxes)
  - Speeches and Shorter Writings
    - "The Hospital of Tomorrow," Maine Hospital Association and Colby College, Waterville: correspondence, speech excerpt and program, 1969 September 10 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - "Reorganization of Community Health Services and the Role of the Hospital," Hospital Management Association: speech excerpt and program, 1969 September 24-26 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Services," University of Colorado School of Medicine, Estes Park: correspondence, speech text and conference material, 1969 September 29 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Services," Michigan Hospitals: tear sheet, 1969 September (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Keynote address, Hospital Credit Forum, Lake George, New York: correspondence and agenda, 1969 October 8-10 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - "The Hospital in the 70s: Center of Community Health Services and Planning," Wisconsin Hospital Association, Milwaukee: correspondence and speech text, 1969 October 15-17 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - "Comprehensive Health Care and the Consumer," Society of Teachers of Family Medicine, Association of American Medical Colleges, Cincinnati: correspondence and speech text, 1969 October 30 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "How Does Comprehensive Health Care Relate to the Health Care Industry?" Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation: reprint, 1969 October (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "Financing Community Health Services and Facilities," Trenton State College: correspondence, 1969 November 24 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Services," O'Conner Hospital, Los Gatos (California): speech text, 1969 December 9 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - What's Ahead For the Decade?--A Consumer Point of View, New Mexico Hospital Association, Albuquerque: speech texts, correspondence and clippings, 1969 December 15-16 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - "Labor Relations in Hospitals," Industrial Relations Research Association: correspondence, notes and conference material, 1969 December (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - "Socio-Economic Forces Affecting the Health Care System," South Carolina Hospital Association, Columbia: correspondence and speech text, 1970 January 23 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - "Organization For Community Health Care," the Cleveland Clinic: correspondence and program, 1970 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - "National Health Insurance: Major Proposals and Issues," United Hospital Fund of New York: speech text and correspondence, 1970 January 29 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - "The Hospital of the Seventies," University of Florida, Gainesville: correspondence and conference program, 1970 February 1-3 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - The Lankenan Hospital, Philadelphia: correspondence, 1970 February 23 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - "Organization for Community Health Care," Urban Policy Institute, Conference on the Future of Health Policy in the Mid-south, Memphis (Tennessee): speech text, correspondence and conference material, 1970 March 6 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - "Organization for Community Health Care," American Hospital Association, Chicago: speech text, notes and correspondence, 1970 March 12 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - The American Assembly, Columbia University: correspondence and conference material, 1970 April 23-26 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - "The Hospital of the Late Seventies," Massachusetts Hospital Association, Wakefield: correspondence and speech text, 1970 May 4 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - "The Paradox of Health Care: Crisis Born of Progress," Governor's Conference on Health and Hospital Services and Costs, New York: conference material, transcripts, and speech text, 1970 May 14-15 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Services," Middle Atlantic Health Congress, Atlantic City: speech text, 1970 May 21 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - "Economic Issues in Medical Care Delivery," Jefferson Medical College, Philadelphia: speech text, 1970 May 27 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - "The Rationalization of Health Services: A Universal Priority," Comprehensive Health Planning Council of Western New York, Inc., Buffalo: correspondence and speech text, 1970 June 4 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - "The Hospital and the Emerging Health Care System," Albert Einstein Medical Center, Philadelphia: correspondence and speech reprint, 1970 June 13 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - "The Hospital of the Seventies," United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, St. Petersburg (Florida): program and correspondence, 1970 June 16-18 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - "The Delivery of Health Care in the 70s," Conference on Shared Issues and Challenges, University of Notre Dame: correspondence and program, 1970 June 27-28 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - "National Health Insurance: Major Proposals, Issues and Goals," American College of Hospital Administrators, San Fransisco: speech introduction and program, 1970 August 24 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - "The Economics of Health Care Delivery," University of Utah College of Medicine, Salt Lake City: speech text, 1970 September 10 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - "How to Plan for Future Roles," National Conference on Pharmacy Manpower, University of California, San Fransisco: speech text, notes and correspondence, 1970 September 10-12 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - "The Communication of Health Information to the Public: Panel Remarks," American Medical Writers Association, New York: speech text, correspondence and program, 1970 September 24-27 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - "National Health Insurance: Issues and Prospects," Washington State Hospital Association, Seattle: correspondence, clippings and program, 1970 October 8 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Services," University of North Carolina at Greensboro: correspondence, speech excerpt and invitation, 1970 October 15 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - "The Hospital and the Emerging Health Care System," University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill: speech text and correspondence, 1970 October 16 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - "Organization of Health Care," Visiting Nurse Association of Camden (New Jersey): speech text and correspondence, 1970 October 22 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - "National Health Insurance: Major Proposals, Issues and Goals," Arizona Hospital Association, Phoenix: correspondence and convention program, 1970 October 28-30 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Strengthening the Financing of Health Care in the United States--A Proposal in Two Parts, Alabama Hospital Association: speech text, correspondence and clippings, 1970 October 30 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - "National Health Insurance: Major Proposals, Issues and Goals," Hackensack Hospital Association: speech text and program, 1970 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - "National Health Insurance: Major Proposals, Issues and Goals," Tulane University: correspondence and speech text, 1970 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - "Major Recent Trends in Health Care and Some Probable Future Developments," Trinity University, San Antonio (Texas): speech text and correspondence, 1970 December 9 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - "The Future Is Not What It Used to Be," Texas Hospital Association, Dallas (Texas): speech text and correspondence, 1970 December 10 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - "Strengthening the Financing of Health Care in the United States," Governor's Steering Committee for Social Problems, New York: text and correspondence, 1970 December 21 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - An Evaluation of the Perloff Report--Ameriplan, Association of Western Hospitals, Las Vegas: speech texts, condensed reprint and correspondence, 1971 January 21 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - "Redefinition of Professional Roles to Assure Personalized Care," Brooklyn-Cumberland Medical Center, New York: speech text and conference material, 1971 January 29 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - "The Role of the University Hospital in Medical Care: Today and Tomorrow," University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine: speech text, correspondence and tear sheet, 1971 February 24 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - "Acceptance Speech, American College of Hospital Administrators' Dean Conley: Award": speech text, correspondence and newsletter, 1971 February 26 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - "Major Recent Trends in Health Care," Montgomery County Medical Society, Dayton (Ohio): speech text, 1971 March 11 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - "Implications of a National Health Insurance Program," University of California, San Fransisco: correspondence, 1971 March 16 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Health Care and Manpower Issues--After the Freeze, National, Rehabilitation Association, Chicago: speech text, correspondence and program, 1971 April 19 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - "Comprehensive Care and the Central Role of the Hospital," University of Pennsylvania: speech text, program and tear sheet from Journal of the American Hospital Association, 1971 April 22 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - "National Health Insurance, An Assessment," New Jersey Welfare Council, North Brunswick: speech text and correspondence, 1971 April 29 (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - "National Health Insurance," Hospital Financial Management Association, Champion (Pennsylvania): program, 1971 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - "The Economics of Health Care and a New Approach to the Problem of National Health Insurance," Onodaga County Medical Society, Syracuse: speech text and correspondence, 1971 May 4 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - "Catastrophic Health Insurance? A Catastrophe!" Medical Economics: tear sheet, 1971 May 10 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - "The Role of the Public Sector in the U.S. Health Care Economy," Ortho Research Foundation, Rariton (New Jersey): speech text, correspondence and notes, 1971 May 25 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - "Major Issues in National Health Insurance," Sun Valley Forum on National Health (Idaho): speech text, 1971 June 20-26 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - "The Nation's Health: Issues for the Future," University of Colorada School of Medicine, Estes Park: speech text and correspondence, 1971 September 28 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - "A Look at the Future: Tomorrow and the Day After Tomorrow," Tennessee Hospital Association, Gatlinburg: correspondence and speech text, 1971 September 30 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - "Health Evaluation in Transition," Society for Advanced Medical Systems, Memphis: correspondence and speech text, 1971 October 6-7 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Health Care and Manpower Issues--After the Freeze, St. Cloud Hospital Forum, St. Cloud (Minnesota): speech text and correspondence, 1971 October 10-13 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Only the Hospital Can Do It All--Now,: tear sheet, 1971 October 12. (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - "Health Care Issues for the Future: Some Short-Run and Long-Run Considerations," Indiana Hospital Association, French Lick: speech text, correspondence and program, 1971 October 27-29 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - "Relationships In Future Health Care Delivery," Association for Hospital Medical Education, Washington, D.C.: speech text and correspondence, 1971 October 28-November 1 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - "Some Key Issues Facing Health Care Planners Today," Western Pennsylvania Comprehensive Health Planning Agency, Inc.: Pittsburgh: speech text, correspondence and program, 1971 November 3 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - "The Economics of Health Care: Some Short-Run and Long-Run Considerations," American College of Hospital Administrators, Bal Harbour (Florida): speech text, correspondence and program, 1971 November 4-6 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - State and Territorial Health Authorities; Directors of State Hospital and Health Facility Construction Programs, Washington, D.C.: correspondence, 1971 December 5 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - "Pressures for Change in Health Care Delivery Systems," American Society of Hospital Pharmacists, Washington D.C.: speech text and correspondence, 1971 December 12-16 (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - "The Rationalization of Health Services: A Universal Priority," Inquiry: reprint, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - "Statements before the Special Subcommittee on Labor," Committee on Education and Labor, U.S. House of Representatives: text of statement, 1972 January 18 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - "Health Care and the Political System: the Sorcerer's Apprentice Revisited," U.S.D.H.E.W., National Center for Health Services Research and Development, San Fransisco: speech text, correspondence and notes, 1972 January 19-22 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - "Health Care and the Political System: the Sorcerer's Apprentice Revisited," Association of University Professors of Opthalmology, Key Biscayne (Florida): speech draft, correspondence and reprints, 1972 January 24 (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - "The Nation's Health: Issues for the Future," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia: correspondence, text and reprints, 1972 January (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - "The Organization and Financing of the Health Care Issues and Directions for the Future," American Journal of Orthopsychiatry: reprints and correspondence, 1972 January (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - Milbank Faculty Fellows and Associates Conference, Mexico City: report and notes, 1972 February 23-26 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - "Death Rates, Lifestyle and National Morale: Two Proposals," Protestant Health Assembly, Chicago: speech text, condensed reprints and correspondence, 1972 March 5-9 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - "The Hospital and the Health Care Crisis," Washington Hospital Center, Washington, D.C.: speech text, draft, reprints and correspondence, 1972 March 21 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - "The Future Role of the Hospital in Health Care Delivery," Mount Sinai Medical Center, New York: correspondence and notes, 1972 March 27 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - "Regulation of Hospitals," the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science: correspondence, text and reprint, 1972 March (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - "Health Care in Transition: Issues for the Future," West Virginia League for Nursing and Health Care, Parkersburg: speech text and program, 1972 April 5-7 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - "The Central Role of the Hospital in Community Health Planning," Alabama Regional Medical Program, Birmingham (Alabama): correspondence and speech text, 1972 April 9 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - "Health Care Finance," University of Alabama School of Medicine and Southern Newspaper Publishers Association Foundation: correspondence, notes and conference material, 1972 April 9-12 (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - "The Hospital and the Health Care Crisis," Kentucky Hospital Association, Louisville: speech text and correspondence, 1972 April 18 (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - "Medical Education and the Community: A Consumer Point of View," Michigan State University, Traverse City: speech text, reprints and correspondence, 1972 April 23-26 (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - "Health Care Priorities 1972: A Consumer Point of View," Blue Cross-Blue Shield Spring Marketing Conference, Chicago: speech text, correspondence and programs, 1972 April 27 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - "The Hospital and the Health Care Delivery System," Indiana University Graduate School of Business: correspondence, speech text and reprint, 1972 May 15 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - "Thoughts on National Health Insurance and Improving the Financing of Health Care, May, 1972," Association of Hospital Personnel Administrators of Greater New York: correspondence and speech text, 1972 May 19 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - "Who's In Charge Here? or Alice Searches for a King in Mediland," Massachusetts Medical Society, Boston: speech texts and correspondence, 1972 May 31 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - "Let's Stop Bypassing Hospitals in Health Systems Planning," Hospital World: interview and reprint, 1972 May (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - "The Hospital and the Health Care Crisis," Bishop Clarkson Memorial Hospital Symposium, Omaha: correspondence, speech text and program, 1972 June 9 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - "Is the Hospital a Public Utility?" North Carolina Hospital Association, Wrightsville Beach: correspondence, notes and program, 1972 June 13-15 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - American Enterprise Institute, Conference on Health Planning, Certificates of Need and Market Entry, Washington, D.C.: correspondence and notes, 1972 June 15-16 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - "Medical Education and the Community: A Consumer Point of View," McMaster University, Hamilton (Ontario): speech text, correspondence and notes, 1972 July 14 (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Some Suggested Goals for the College of Medicine and Dentistry of New Jersey--1985, CMDNJ Long Range Planning Committee: text, 1972 July (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - "Role of Leadership in Developing Hospitals as Centers for Community Health Service," Honolulu: program, correspondence and notes, 1972 August 12-23 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - "Federally Supported Universal Health Care Coverage: the Consumer's Expectations," Health Industries Association, Buck Hill Falls (Pennsylvania): speech text and correspondence, 1972 September 12-15 (Box 13, Folder 136)
    - "Statement before Commissioner: Herbert S. Dennenberg," Insurance Department, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania: excerpt reprint and press release, 1972 September 25 (Box 13, Folder 137)
    - "State Regulation as Related to Health Care," Hospital Financial Management Association, Albany: correspondence and speech text, 1972 September 26-29 (Box 13, Folder 138)
    - "The Hospital in the Emerging Health Care System," Illinois Hospital Association, Chicago: speech text, correspondence and program, 1972 October 25-27 (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - "Who's In Charge Here? or Alice Searches for a King in Mediland," New England Journal of Medicine: text, correspondence and reprints, 1972 October 26 (Box 13, Folder 140)
    - "Medical Education and the Community: A Consumer Point of View," New England Hospital Association, Hospital Medical Staff Conference, Hyannis (Massachusetts): speech text, correspondence and program, 1972 October 30 (Box 13, Folder 141)
    - "Who's in Charge Here? or Alice Searches for a King in Mediland," Harold Bruon Society for Medical Research, San Fransisco: correspondence, text and agenda, 1972 November 21 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - "Remedy for Hospitals," in The New York Times: correspondence and copies, 1972 November 24 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - "The Changing Health Care Scene: A Post-Election View," Inauguration of the School of Nursing, University of Rochester: correspondence, text and agenda, 1972 December 8-9 (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - "Career Process of Health Professionals: Putting Research Into Action," American Association for the Advancement of Science Symposium: speeches, correspondence and commentary, 1972 December 27 (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - To Know--or Die: The Challenge to Consumer Health Education, Middle Atlantic Health Congress, Atlantic City: text, correspondence and programs, 1973 January 29 (Box 14, Folder 146)
    - "Redefining Health Issues and Programs for the Future," Mennonite Medical Association and Center for Discipleship, Division of Nursing, Goshen College: correspondence and text, 1973 February 1 (Box 14, Folder 147)
    - "Health Care in the Seventies: A Look to the Future," Mennonite Medical Association and Center for Discipleship, Division of Nursing, Goshen College: correspondence and text, 1973 February 2 (Box 14, Folder 148)
    - "The Increasingly Controlled Hospital Environment: Implications for Management Social and Organizational Factors," American College of Hospital Administrators, 16th Annual Conference: correspondence and text, 1973 February 22 (Box 14, Folder 149)
    - "State Regulation of Hospitals and Health Care: The New Jersey Story," Special Meeting, Ohio Department of Health, Columbus: correspondence, text and notes, 1973 March 20 (Box 14, Folder 150)
    - "A Commonsense Strategy for Health Care in the Seventies," University of Washington School of Medicine Graduate Program: text, reprint as Prism article, and correspondence, 1973 April 5-6 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - "The Challenge to the Voluntary Hospital: New Jersey 1973," address at dedication of Rahway Hospital's new Wing: correspondence and text, 1973 May 12 (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - "Hospitals: What Reluctance?" Veteran's Administration Hospital and the Greater Cincinnati Hospital Council, 14th Annual Seminar," correspondence and copies of article, 1973 May 16 (Box 14, Folder 153)
    - "Digestive Disease Health Care," Summary of Workshop B-1, Second Conference on Digestive Disease as a National Problem, National Institutes for Health: correspondence and text, 1973 May 18 (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - "Two Suggestions for Humanizing Health," commencement address, Health Services Center, State University of New York at Stony Brook: text, correspondence and reprints, 1973 June 17 (Box 14, Folder 155)
    - "Dimensions of External Pressures and Controls on the Health Care Institution (A Not-So-New-Ballgame)," New Hampshire Hospital Association: correspondence and text, 1973 June 21 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - "P.S.R.O.: Friend or Foe?" New England Journal of Medicine: text and correspondence, 1973 August 9 (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - "Hospital Labor-Management Relations: Current Status and Prospects," University of Southern California and Hawaii, 16th Annual Postgraduate Refresher Course: correspondence and text, 1973 August 17 (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - "Patient Needs in the Years Ahead," Mountainside Hospital Medical Symposium New Jersey: text and correspondence, 1973 September 22 (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - "The Hospital's Responsibility for Community Health Services," Hunterdon Medical Center and Princeton University Symposium, "20 Years of Community Medicine,": text, correspondence and notes, 1973 October 6 (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - "Patient's Bill of Rights: A Significant Aspect of the Consumer Revolution," with Nancy Quinn, New Jersey State Nurses Association: text and correspondence, 1973 October 11 (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - "The Hospital as a Management System: From Responsibility to Accountability," New York Catholic Health Congress: correspondence and newsletter, 1973 October 13 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - "The Hospital as a Management System: From Responsiblity to Accountability," Ontario Hospital Association: text, correspondence and notes, 1973 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - "The New Jersey Community Health Education Program," opening statement before the United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare Health Insurance Benefits Advisory Council, 1973 November 16 (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - "The Hospital in the Evolving Health Care System," the Mark Berke Memorial Lecture, Mount Zion Hospital and Medical Center: texts, correspondence and notes, 1973 November 21 (Box 15, Folder 165)
    - "Patient Needs in the Years Ahead," American Hospital Association, National Conference on Public-General Hospitals, San Antonio (Texas): text, correspondence and notes, 1973 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 166)
    - "Adapting Institutions to Changing Needs," American Hospital Association, National Conference on Public-General Hospitals, San Antonio (Texas): reprints and correspondence, 1973 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 167)
    - Booz, Allen and Hamilton, Inc., conference on Current Trends in the Evolution of Health Care: correspondence and notes, 1973 November 29-December 1 (Box 15, Folder 168)
    - "Community Health Education, A Challenge to Hospital and Staff," Morristown Memorial Hospital Community Health Education Department: text and notes, 1973 December 3 (Box 15, Folder 169)
    - "Franchising: A New Role for Hospitals in a Changing Health Care System," George Washington University Health Staff seminar: text and correspondence, 1973 December 10 (Box 15, Folder 170)